

SeyedAmin Hosseini
Tehran

00989153528270 / amin.hoseiny@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/amin--hosseini (LinkedIn) amin.hoseiny@hotmail.com (Skype)

<u>Summary</u>

A **PHP Web Developer** with **8+ years** of experience in the field of Web Technology with expertise in **Symfony** to build e-commerce sites with the aim of improving sales. Experience with Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC). Requirement experience in developing Web services and **RESTful** services. Sound Knowledge in **O**bject **O**riented **P**rogramming. Ability to work in an agile environment and meet the deadlines Capable of quickly learning and delivering solutions Good Project Management and Inter-personal skills I enjoy creating elegant solutions to complex problems.

Skills

- 8+ years of experience in PHP, MySQL LAMP stack
- 8+ years of experience with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- **2+ years** of experience with the **Symfony** PHP Framework
- 5+ years extensive experience of developing with MVC frameworks
- 4+ years of experience with BootStrap, J-Query Framework and Responsive Web Design
- Knowledge in OOP principles (Design patterns, SOLID)
- Experience working with RESTful Web Services
- Familiarity with NoSQL databases like MongoDB, Redis
- Experience in a collaborative development environment using Git and Scram
- Familiar Unit testing with **PHPUnit**
- Willing to learn Node.js

Experience

PHP Web Developer – Arad Emertat, Tehran (Full Time)

02/2017 - Present

- Increased 40% Performance of **Technical University's Book Reader** Admin Panel by Migration from **PHP Klein** to **Symfony** Freamwork
- Reduced 100% of data synchronization times between accounting software and online store with developing an API.
- Improved of the e-commerce sites warranty process by automating and developing a Warranty Management System.
- 80% of websites built were of the e-commerce variety.
- Designed, programmed and managed over 30+ websites in the last 2 years.
- Created over +30 custom modules such as Payment and Carrier for websites built were by the PrestaShop.
- Write a code for Migration Database store from previous version to last version.
- Increased 37% sales in e-commerce sites by improvement of checkout process with write cart modules.

- Developed and designed a Book Readers Web Admin App for Technical Universities.
- Launch **official Apple Service Iran** website with practical modules such as Advanced Support System, Smart Blog, Marketplace, Telegram Robot.
- Developed and designed module for **20+** websites using **PHP** with **OOP**.
- Improve the performance of websites with Experience in template building, writing custom modules, and site architecture.

PHP Web Developer – Lord System, Neyshabour (Full Time)

04/2008 - 08/2012

- Design and implementation of online store using PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Designing Web-Based **After-Sales Service** Portal
- Add new features to the website
- Increased annual sales revenues by an average of 71% perform keyword research and SEO analysis and recommendations.

Education

Montazeri Technical University, Mashhad, Iran – Associate Degree in Software Engineering.

2002 - 2005

Language

- English Professional working proficiency (B1)
- **Deutsch** Limited working proficiency (A1)

<u>Projects</u>

- Book Reader Web and Mobile Application Technical and Vocational University (tvu.ac.ir)
- Developed course enrollment and management system For Meyar Sanat Co
- Employee Management System Agri Bank

Personal Skills

- Work effectively as a team, supporting other members of the team
- Able to self-prioritize tasks
- Analytical and problem solving skills
- Willing to travel
- Flexible and adaptable to any work situation
- Interested in learning the latest technology